A Guide to the Lunenburg County (Va.) Records, circa 1743-1936
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Lunenburg County (Va.) Records, circa 1743-1936
The Library of Virginia
1012143, 1046171, 1120918-1120925, 1175961, 1175964, 1180244-1180245, 1180248-1180250, 1180252-1180255
21 boxes--19 found at State Records Center--Archives Annex, Library of Virginia and 2 (1046171, 1120921) found at Library of Virginia.
Lunenburg County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in a transfer of court records from Lunenburg County. Box 1046171 includes Accession number 43095. Boxes 1175961 and 1175964 were transferred under Accession number 42852.
Historical Information
Lunenburg County was named for King George II, duke of Brunswick-Luneburg, a German possesion of the Hanoverian Kings of England. The county was formed from Brunswick County on 1 May 1746. Part of Charlotte County was added in 1777.
Scope and Content
Lunenburg County (Va.) Records, circa 1743-1936, consist of the following series: Court Records (subfield series include Judgments, Criminal Records, Chancery Records and Clerks' Records), Bonds/Commissions/Oaths, Road and Bridge Records, Tax and Fiscal Records, Land Records, Justice of the Peace Records, Election Records, County Administrative Records: Board of Supervisors Records: Road and Bridge Records, Overseers of the Poor Records and Treasurer's Records), Miscellaneous Records, Fiduciary Records, School Records and Military and Pension Records.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Lunenburg County Records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult "A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm" found on the Library of Virginia's web site.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Lunenburg County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Subjects:
Public records--Virginia--Lunenburg County.
Geographical Names:
Lunenburg County (Va.)--History.
Genre and Form Terms:
Local government records--Virginia--Lunenburg County.
Contents List
- Records, circa 1745-1920
  Court Records: Judgments and Criminal Records; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; Road and Bridge Records; Tax and Fiscal Records. Unprocessed.
- Records, circa 1876-1933
  Court Records: Judgments, Criminal Records, Orphan Chancery; Clerks' Records: Official and Personal Papers of John Yates (includes Accession number 43095 - unprocessed), Assessments of Clerks of Court, Reports of Clerks of Court; Tax and Fiscal Records: County Claims, Commonwealth Claims, Records Related to Personal Property Taxes, Receipts for Auditor of Public Accounts; Land Records: Plats, (1888, 1890, 1901.)
- Records, 1833-1861
  Court Records: Judgments and Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes; Justice of the Peace Records; Road and Bridge Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Election Records.
- Records, 1861-1869
  Court Records: Judgments and Criminal Records:Commonwealth Causes; Justice of the Peace Records; Road and Bridge Records; Tax and Fiscal Records.
- Records, 1818-1879
  Court Records: Judgments and Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes; Justice of the Peace Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; County Administrative Records: Board of Supervisors Records: Road and Bridge Records.
- Records, 1879-1904
  Court Records: Judgments, Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes, Clerks' Records (John L. Yates); Justice of the Peace Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Election Records; County Administrative Records: Board of Supervisors Records: Road and Bridge Records.
- Records, 1885-1888
- Records, 1823-1907
- Records, 1897-1901
- Records, circa 1743-1931
  Court Records: Judgments: Subpoenas and Criminal Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Road and Bridge Records; Miscellaneous Records: Estray papers; Land Records: Mill petitions.
- Records, 1751-1911
  Road and Bridge Records: Road Petition: Petition for Bridge: Ferry Bond, 1753-1755. Miscellaneous Records: Power of Attorney: Crop and Vendor Liens: Estray Papers, 1751-1911. Tax and Fiscal Records: Peronal Property Tax Vouchers (Slaves Named): Personal Property Tax Draft List, 1782. Bonds/Oaths/Commissions: Commissions for Justice of the Peace and Sheriff: Bonds for Constables: Clerk's Bonds: Commissions for Clerk of Superior Court and Court Records: Judgments: Indemnity Bonds, 1783-1840. Tax and Fiscal Records: Ordinary License Bonds, 1837-1839. County Administrative Records: Overseers of the Poor Records: Overseers of the Poor Elected, Lower District, 1819-1835. Fiduciary Records: Administrator's Bond, 1831. School Records: School Commissioner's Report. County Administrative Records: Treasurer's Records: Annual Account of the Treasurer, 1821-1833. UNPROCESSED. Accession number 42852.
- Records, circa 1750-1936
  Land Records: List of Transfers: Index to Deeds A-B, 1870-1936. Fiduciary Records: Papers Related to the Estate of James Cocke, circa 1750. UNPROCESSED. Accession number 42852.
- Records, circa 1800-1924
  Court Records: Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes and Judgments; County Administrative Records: Board of Supervisors Records: Road and Bridge Records; Tax and Fiscal Records. Unprocessed.
- Records, circa 1745-1900
  Court Records: Judgments and Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes; Road and Bridge Records; Land Records: Mill petitions; Tax and Fiscal Records.
- Records, circa 1800-1924
  Court Records: Judgments and Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes; Road and Bridge Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Land Records: Mill petitions; Military and Pension Records. Unprocessed.
- Records, circa 1800-1924
- Records, circa 1745-1880
  Court Records: Judgments and Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes; Road and Bridge Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Land Records: Mill petitions; Military and Pension Records: Pension Petitions. Unprocessed.
- Records, circa 1800-1924
  Court Records: Judgments and Court Records: Commonwealth Causes; Road and Bridge Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Land Records: Mill petitions; Military and Pension Records. Unprocessed.
- Records, circa 1800-1900
- Records, circa 1745-1900
  Court Records: Judgments and Court Records: Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes; Road and Bridge Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Land Records: Mill petitions; Military and Pension Records. Unprocessed.
- Records, circa 1900-1920
  Court Records: Judgments and Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes; Tax and Fiscal Records. Unprocessed.